Guide to the Washington D.C. Election Data papers, 1914-2001 MS2205
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Washington D.C. Election Data collection
1914-2001
1974-1994
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Henig, Jeffrey R.
MS2205
5.25 Linear Feet
The materials of this series include election data, election results, reports, clippings, essays, articles, maps, and notes. They range in date from 1914 to 2001, but the bulk of the material dates from 1970 to 1995. They represent material produced and/or collected by Professor Jeffrey R. Henig while he worked at the George Washington Center for Washington Area Studies and in the Department of Political Science.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement note
Organized into two series: Election data and Subject files.
Biographical note
Jeffrey R. Henig (1951- ) is Professor of Political Science & Education at Teachers College and Professor of Political Science at Columbia University. Formerly, Henig taught at the George Washington University, where he served as the Director of the Center for Washington Area Studies and as Professor and Chair in the Department of Political Science. He earned his B.A. at Cornell University in 1973 and his Ph.D. at Northwestern University in 1978. His research has focused on the boundary between private action and public action in addressing social problems. He is the author or co-author of Neighborhood Mobilization: Redevelopment and Response (Rutgers, 1982), Public Policy and Federalism (St. Martins, 1985), Rethinking School Choice: Limits of the Market Metaphor (Princeton, 1994), Shrinking the State: The Political Underpinnings of Privatization (Cambridge, 1998), The Color of School Reform: Race, Politics and the Challenge of Urban Education (Princeton, 1999), which the Urban Politics Section of the American Political Science Association named the best book written on urban politics in 1999; and Building Civic Capacity: The Politics of Reforming Urban Schools (Kansas, 2001), which the Urban Politics Section of the American Political Science Association named the best book written on urban politics in 2001.
Scope and Contents note
The materials of this collection include election data, election results, reports, clippings, essays, articles, maps, census data, organization records, newsletters, and notes. They range in date from 1914 to 2001, but the bulk of the material dates from 1970 to 1995. They represent material produced and/or collected by Professor Jeffrey R. Henig while he worked at the George Washington Center for Washington Area Studies and in the Department of Political Science. Most of the material relates to Washington DC elections, neighborhoods, politicians, and demographic information. A small amount of the material relates to the GW Institute of Public Policy. The material includes several essays written by Professor Henig. The collection was transferred from the George Washington Institute of Public Policy in 2006.
Immediate Source of Acquition note
Transferred by George Washington Institute of Public Policy, 08/11/2006 (2007.003)
Elections -- Washington (D.C.); Elections
- Election data, 1974-2000; 1974-1994; Series 1; 2.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement note
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents note
  The materials of this series include election data, election results, reports, clippings, and essays. They range in date from 1974 to 2000. They represent material relating ot DC elections collected by Professor Jeffrey R. Henig while he worked at the George Washington Center for Washington Area Studies and in the Department of Political Science.
  - Sept. 10, 1974 Primary, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Nov. 4, 1974 General (Council and School Board), Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1974 Misc, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - May 4, 1976 Presus Primary, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - May 4, 1976 Primary Rep. National Committee, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sept. 14, 1976 Primary, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Nov. 13, 1976 General, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sept. 12, 1978 Primary, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1978 City Council, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1978 Primary, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Nov. 7, 1978 General, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sept. 4, 1980 Primary, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sept. 9, 1980 Primary, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - May 7, 1980 Presus Primary, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - May 7, 1980 Presus Primary Continued, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nov. 7. 1980 General, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Ward breakdown of votes 09/14/1982 Primary, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1982, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Nov. 2, 1982 Primary, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Nov. 2, 1982 General, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Turnout Figuers 1982, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Pct Breadowns 1984 At Large Primary - Schwartz vs. Moore, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Sept. 11, 1984 Primary, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Nov. 6, 1984 General, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Nov. 1984, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1986 Mayoral, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Sept. 9, 1986 Primary, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Nov. 1986 General, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - May 3, 1988 Presus Primary, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - May 3, 1988 Presus Primary, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - September 13, 1988 Primary, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Nov. 8, 1988 General, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Sept. 11, 1990 Primary, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Nov. 6, 1990 General, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - DC Mayoral Election 1990, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - September 15, 1992 DC Council Primary Election, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 11/3/1992 unoffical election results, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 11/3/1992 General Election offical results, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Special Elec. Sept. 1993, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Council chair race 1993, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Mayoral Election 1994, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - DC Primary Election 1994, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Dem. Prim. 1994, Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Gen. F 1994 DC General Election, Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - DC Elections - Race - Lee - 1994, Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1997 Special Elect. At Large, Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - DC Primary Election 09/15/1998, Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - DC General Election 11/03/1998, Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Gen. 98, 1998; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Mayoral 1998, Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Spec. Elect. School Board Chater 06/27/2000, Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Subject files, 1914-2001; 1970-1998; Series 2; 2.75 Linear Feet
  Series is arranged alphabetically, but politician files and DC-Metro regional/neighborhood files are grouped at the end of the series.
  The materials of this series include clippings, essays, articles, maps, reports, census data, organization records, newsletters, and notes. They range in date from 1914 to 2001, but the bulk of the material dates from 1970 to 1995. They represent material produced and/or collected by Professor Jeffrey R. Henig while he worked at the George Washington Center for Washington Area Studies and in the Department of Political Science.. Most of the material relates to Washington DC elections, neighborhoods, politicians, and demographic information. A small amount of the material relates to the GW Institute of Public Policy. The material includes several essays written by Professor Henig.
  - Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, 1980-1986; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Analysis [1 of 2], 1978-1991; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Analysis [2 of 2], 1978-1991; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Asians, 1991; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Census, 1980-1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Census 1990, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Center for Washington Area Studies book sales, 1989-1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - City council misc., 1976-1986; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - DC area growth, 1990-1991; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - DC Board of Elections and Ethics, 1990-1991; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - DC budget crisis [1 of 2], 1993-1994; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - DC budget crisis [2 of 2], 1993-1995; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - DC/Congress, 1991-1998; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - DC Control Board, 1995-1998; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - DC Council Journal, 1992-1993; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - DC crime, 1990-1994; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - DC data, 1970-1980; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - DC DHCD, 1991-1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - DC elections, 1990-1991; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - DC Elections Project, 1990-1991; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - DC Homeless Shelter Initiative, 1982-1992; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - DC public and assisted housing, 1994; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - DC subcommittees documents, 1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - DC vs. U.S., 1992; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Dem. code, 1970-*1990; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Election data and maps, 1989-1997; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Elections codebook, 1988-1991; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Gentrification - Adams Morgan, 1979-1984; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Gentrification - DC, 1985-1987; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Gentrification - tax changes, 1977-1982; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - GOP, 1981-1982; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Hispanics, 1992-1994; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Historical, 1974-1980; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Historical preservation DC [1 of 2], 1973-1985; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Historical preservation DC [2 of 2], 1973-1985; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Historical preservation - Lincoln Theater, 1993; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Internationalization of DC, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Laws Relating to Elections, 1977; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Maps, 1989-1990; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Metro, 1991-1994; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Misc. clippings, 1982-1991; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Misc. clippings, 1982; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Multiculturalism DC, 1991-1992; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - NIMBY article [1 of 2], 1981-1993; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - NIMBY article [2 of 2], 1981-1993; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - NIMBY article revised, 1993-1994; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Other research centers, 1988; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Statehood, 1974; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Urban alums, 1998; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Urban history, 1978; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Voters guides, 1982-1990; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Voter turnout League of Women Voters, 1996-2001; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Washington and area history, 1975-1986; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - C. Alexander, 1972-1974; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Marion Barry, 1978-1986; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Dave Clarke, 1982-1986; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - A. Dixon, undated; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Dixon Admin., 1991-1993; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Arthur Fletcher, 1978; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - C. Jarvis, undated; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Kane, Betty, 1981-1986; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - E. Brooke Lee, 1982; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - D. Moore, 1978; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - J. Moore, undated; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - John Ray, 1982; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Schwartz, Carol, 1981-1986; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - M. Turner, 1989-1990; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Sterling Tucker, 1978; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Walter Washington, 1978; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Adams Morgan, 1978-1990; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Alexandria, 1976-1988; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Anacostia, 1977-1985; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Annopolis, 1979-1984; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Capitol Hill, 1950-1986; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Dupont Circle, 1976-1986; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Georgetown, 1977-1979; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Foggy Bottom, 1959-1980; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - H Street U.R., 1977-1987; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Kalorama Circle, 1939-1986; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - LeDroit Park, 1992; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Logan Circle, 1975-1987; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Montgomery County, 1987-1991; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Mount Pleasant [1 of 2], 1914-1979; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Mount Pleasant [2 of 2], 1976-1991; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Prince George's County, 1991-1994; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Rosslyn, 1978; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Shaw 5th St - 14th St NW, 1983-1993; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Southwest DC urban renewal, Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Westend DC urban redevelopment, 1977; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 7)